

ANNELISE N. SMITH

UX DESIGN AND RESEARCH

annelisesmithux@gmail.com // anoelles.github.io

SKILLS

User Research
Usability Testing
Ethnography
Persona Development
Wireframing
Journey Mapping
Content Analysis
Paper Prototyping
Mobile Experience Design
Axure
Sketch
InVision
OmniGraffle
Adobe Illustrator
HTML/CSS

EDUCATION

UX Design ImmersiveGeneral Assembly Seattle
Nov 2016

User Experience: UX Fundamentals Course School of Visual Concepts Nov 2015

MA in Human Development Washington State University Prevention Science Track May 2013

BA in Social Sciences
Washington State University
Minors in German and
Ethnic Studies
May 2011

ABOUT ME

I'm a **UX designer** and **researcher** with a background in **health promotion** and experience applying **user-centered methodologies** to identify core user needs and motivations. My super power is translating these insights into **evidence-based designs** that meet business goals. Armed with a **creative** yet **analytical mind**, I have a knack for quickly building **genuine connections** with others and I approach challenges with an enthusiasm that naturally motivates those around me.

EXPERIENCE

Designer in Residence // General Assembly // Seattle, WA // Jan 2016 - present

Teach user experience design and user interaction fundamentals in a 10-week immersive UX design course; update and design curriculum to align with current industry standards; provide design critiques and feedback on mobile and web design projects; organize a campus-wide hackathon; provide student support and mentoring; oversee class logistics.

UX Researcher // Dive Around the Clock // Seattle, WA // Oct 2016 - present

Improve alignment of website with user needs through primary user research including interviews, usability testing, and behavioral observation; utilize IA principles and develop site maps/wireframes that enable intuitive navigation and increase click-through to donation and volunteer registration tasks; create new visual branding and style guide.

Field Marketing Specialist // Publicis Hawkeye // Seattle, WA // Oct 2015-Aug 2016

Devise, organize, and execute guerrilla marketing campaigns to drive product awareness and foster brand loyalty

Investigator // WA Child Protective Services // Tacoma, WA // Aug 2014- Oct 2015

Conduct in-home interviews and rapport-building to identify core family problems and make critical legal decisions under limited time constraints and in high-stress situations; facilitate creative solutions to child safety problems using existing family and community resources; create accurate documentation in compliance with federal mandates.

Site Coordinator // Communities in Schools // Lakewood, WA // Aug 2013- Oct 2014

Collaborate with student, family, school, and community stakeholders to identify core student needs and secure community-level resources for at-risk students.

Research Coordinator // Washington State University // Pullman, WA // Aug 2011- July 2013

Create and oversee implementation of data collection and analysis timeline; collaborate as author on scholarly publications; write research briefs and literature reviews to support evidence-based decision making; develop outcome evaluation plans for existing health promotion programs; design, implement, and evaluate social media health campaigns.